Process Redesign and the Five Sigma Wall
Welcome back to this session on performance benchmarks.
What we have here is a set of benchmarking data.
What I’d like to emphasize here, is this is the Z value's based on raw data,
Z.st or short-term Sigma capability.
Now, we see that in graphical form, but I want to focus on the histogram.
So, that we can see this chart in a little more pure form.
Now this is very interesting. Now, what we have is on the horizontal scale is Sigma capability
and the vertical scale is just frequency count.
So we're looking at a histogram of the Sigma’s, if you will,
across that wave of master black belts.
We, see this same graph over and over. What I want to focus on, is look at this.
The modal condition is 4, the average is about 3-1/2.
Very typical of what we see. But look out here in this tail.
Wow, it suddenly builds up in Sigma and then quickly falls off, starts to shoot up again.
This is what I call the 5 Sigma wall.
You can see it's almost as if there is an invisible wall about five Sigma.
That is suddenly truncating, what would otherwise be a normal distribution.
Well here is why that exists.
We can improve up to the limit of our ability to measure.
And we tend to measure, about one digit further
than what we control.
So, once we have improved, we've now lost
our granularity to improve further.
In other words, we can no longer detect more beneficial change.
And that's the five Sigma wall.
It also tends to be related to the limit of the design.
The design capability is about five.
The production capability is about 3-1/2, on average.
So we’ve got about a 1 1/2 Sigma differential.
Then we have a few out here around six.
Which says this, sometimes we achieve Six Sigma even by mistake.
We get it, if there is enough activity going on.
But nonetheless, take a look at that histogram. We tend to see that over and over.
This basically says that in order to go past
Five Sigma, we’ve got to redesign the product or service.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.